Bradley Woods

Mobile: 07846 258038 | Email: bradleywoods4@gmail.com Portfolio: github.com/bradley-woods

A highly driven and adaptable Mechanical turned DevOps engineer with over four years of problem-solving experience. Committed to continuous learning, I have completed the Cisco DevNet bootcamp, achieved certifications in Kubernetes and AWS, and currently I am pursuing an MSc in Computer Science at the University of Bath to broaden my knowledge. My journey into DevOps began at a manufacturing plant, experiencing automation and lean principles, before gaining professional DevOps training. Overall, these accomplishments reflect my skills and dedication to becoming a successful DevOps engineer.

EXPERIENCE

Sparta Global - Junior DevOps Engineer

APRIL 2023 - PRESENT

- Contracted to one of Sparta Global's public sector clients to help support their applications, continuing to gain experience with the cloud and containers using Kubernetes.
- Trained on DevOps methodologies; to collaborate with development and operations teams to automate deployment of applications to different environments.
- Developed knowledge and skills of Linux, Virtualisation, IaC tools (Terraform, Ansible), CI/CD using Jenkins, container technologies (Docker, Kubernetes) and cloud services such as AWS and Azure.

Scottish Tech Army - Volunteer Platform Engineer

OCTOBER 2022 - PRESENT

- Involved in improving different charities' platforms and infrastructure using AWS cloud services.
- Collaborate with engineers to resolve problems using tools such as AWS CDK and Python Boto3.

MSCM - Advanced Engineer

MARCH 2022 - FEBRUARY 2023

- Implemented continuous improvement throughout the department. This included automating design calculations using Microsoft Excel VBA, increasing productivity of engineers.
- Assisted the IT department with the integration of a new cloud-based ERP system and produced a smart part numbering system. Also, automated manual tasks using Python scripting.

MSCM - Junior Design Engineer

NOVEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2022

• Proven track record in developing relationships with key clients and stakeholders, collaborating on a range of projects to successfully deliver engineering solutions in the energy sector.

Brunel Innovation Centre, TWI - Project Technical Assistant

SEPTEMBER 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2018

 Responsible for the mechanical design of electronics enclosures and management of the R&D lab's 3D printers, which were used to produce prototypes for projects throughout the company.

EDUCATION

University of Bath - Master of Science (MSc) in Computer Science

SEPTEMBER 2023 - PRESENT

 Currently pursuing a degree in computer science part-time to broaden knowledge on key areas such as programming, software engineering, databases and cloud, artificial intelligence and cybersecurity.

The Open University/Cisco - Skills Bootcamp in Development and Networking (DevNet) OCTOBER 2022 - MARCH 2023

 Successfully completed the Cisco certified programme led by The Open University. Developed skills in network fundamentals, software development, infrastructure and automation, APIs, application deployment, security and cloud computing.

Brunel University London - Master of Engineering (MEng) in Mechanical Engineering SEPTEMBER 2014 - JULY 2019

Awarded First Class Honours and successfully completed two major projects on control systems
including the design of a highly manoeuvrable and stable light tool handling UAV for infrastructure
monitoring and optimal design of a fuel cell system.

SKILLS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA).
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, working towards Solutions Architect Associate.
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900).
- Cisco DevNet Associate certification.
- Experience with technical tools such as Python, Java, Bash, Linux, Docker, Jenkins and Terraform.
- Experience with collaboration tools such as Jira, Confluence, Trello and Slack.
- Microsoft Office suite including Word, Powerpoint, Excel, Teams, Outlook and OneNote.
- Duke of Edinburgh Bronze, Silver and Gold Awards.
- National Citizen Service: The Challenge.

INTERESTS

- Keeping up-to-date with the latest technologies through reading books and online articles.
- Outdoor adventures summited five mountains, ready to tackle my next challenge!
- Activities such as bouldering, running and hiking, participating in my first half marathon in 2024.

REFERENCES

Available on request.